why is the infinite sum of the powers of
one-third called a geometric series how
can we make sense of the value of this
sum and what does it have to do with
geometry imagine a rectangle with area
one that can be subdivided into three
congruent rectangles each similar to the
original if we shade the top rectangle
we've shaded one third of the area now
we can repeat this process each time we
shade one of the rectangles and we take
the central rectangle and decompose it
into three congruent rectangles shading
one and continuing indefinitely if we do
this process forever or infinitely it
turns out that we have shaded exactly
the infinite sum one-third plus
one-third squared and so on of the
rectangle
but amazingly we see that this shaded
sum fills in exactly half of the
original rectangle since the original
rectangle had an area of one the
infinite sum has an area of one-half